# ANAND ANILKUMAR NAIR

# IT Support | Web Developer | Network Support | Cybersecurity Analyst

https://www.itsmeanand.com | anand@itsmeanand.com | www.linkedin.com/in/anandanair

#### **SUMMARY**

IT Support and Cybersecurity Specialist with 4+ years of experience in incident management, network support, and software development. Developed Click4IT, reducing IT request resolution time by 40%. Built an Al-powered phishing detection Chrome extension to enhance cybersecurity.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development Basic Network Configuration and Troubleshooting

Software Development Fundamentals of Cybersecurity

Incident management Linux and Windows Operating Systems

Application support Python Basics for Scripting

Remote desktop support Knowledge of Networking Protocols (e.g., TCP/IP,

DNS)

Asset management Hardware installation

Mobile device management

**End-user training** 

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Click2View - IT & Technical Support Specialist

Jun 2023 - Aug 2024

- Defined and enforced cybersecurity policies to protect IT assets.
- Managed cloud storage, access controls, and digital records.
- Developed Click4IT portal using React JS and Firebase, streamlining inventory management, equipment booking, and integrating an in-house ChatGPT Assistant for internal IT support.
- Contributed to the development of a new customer-facing website for Click2View.
- Provided on-site and remote IT support and prevented and handled IT incidents effectively.
- Onboarded new staff on IT tools and software and offboarded departing staff.
- Managed passwords and obtained digital attestations for compliance and sales reasons.

#### Micron Technology - IT Field Service Technologist

Jul 2022 - Jan 2023

- Configured software, devices, and hardware to establish employee workstations.
- Resolved network issues impacting connectivity to user devices, manufacturing tools and other fab equipment.
- Automated solutions using PowerShell scripting.
- Received a rating of 4 (Above Expectations) for performance.

### Micron Technology - IT Support Technologist

Jun 2020 - Jun 2022

- Worked with customers to understand needs and provide excellent service within specific timeframes.
- Gained knowledge in using Service Now and BMC Remedy.
- Participated in continuous improvement by creating web applications to automate many solutions using ASP.net, JavaScript, Powershell and SQL.
- Received rating 4 (Above Expectations) and got promoted to Shift Lead within the first year.

# **SwiftX Solutions - Front-end Developer (Intern)**

Jul 2019 - Feb 2020

- Collaborated on tasks adhering to Scrum framework principles.
- Used React, Vue, SQL, and HTML to develop app solutions.
- Resolved technical issues through debugging processes.
- Designed and developed maintainable software solutions tailored to align with business goals.
- Worked closely with UX and UI Designers to implement their visual designs into functional code.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science (Hons) Cybersecurity and Networks**

Aug 2023 - Sep 2024

Teesside University

• Major Project: Developed Phishing Detection Chrome Extension using AI to identify malicious URLs and enhance online security.

#### **Diploma in Information Technology**

April 2017 - May 2020

Temasek Polytechnic

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Click4IT – Internal IT Portal

- Technologies used: React.js, Firebase, OpenAl API
- Built for Click2View employees to manage IT assets, HR, subscriptions, and internal support with a AI-powered assistant.

#### Al-Powered Portfolio – itsmeanand.com

- o Technologies used: Next.js (TS, Tailwind), Supabase, Gemini Al, RAG
- Personal website with a smart assistant that answers questions based on portfolio data.
  Includes full admin panel and vector search integration.

# • Autonomous Blog – blog.itsmeanand.com

- Technologies used: Next.js, Supabase, Gemini Al, Automation
- Fully Al-driven blog that auto-generates and publishes tech articles twice daily using automated pipelines (topic > research > content > image > publish).

# • Phishing Detection Extension

- o Technologies used: Node.js, ML, Chrome API, Firebase
- Trained ML model to detect phishing URLs in real-time via a Chrome extension with dynamic alerts and logging.

# Workflow & Remote Ops Tools

- o Technologies used: React.js, ASP.NET MVC, PowerShell, SSMS
- Developed tools for license/chop approval workflows and remote app installs/commands across devices.

# Other Projects

- Canva-like design tool (React, Firebase) with user publishing https://react-portfoliowebsite-ea2dc.web.app
- Personal couples chat app (Flutter, Firebase)

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- Learn to Program: The Fundamentals (Python) course authorized by University of Toronto and offered through Coursera.
- Google Certificate on Technical Support Fundamentals.
- Received 2 Certificates for the completion of 2 projects in Micron.
- Awarded certificate of appreciation for contributing in Asia Pacific Youth Robotics Competition 2017.

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Languages: English, Malayalam, Tamil, Hindi
- · Activities and Hobbies:
  - Music Production: Learning to compose and produce music.
  - Badminton: Passionate player, continuously improving skills.
  - Travel: Enthusiastic traveler, completed an All India motorcycle trip.